Ira Shokar

🖂 i.j.s.shokar@maths.cam.ac.uk 🐧 github.ira-shokar.github.io 🐐 Department Page 🗹 Text in blue are links

PhD Student at the University of Cambridge's Department of Applied Mathematics & Theoretical Physics researching applications of Machine Learning to Atmospheric Fluid Dynamics.

Technical Skills: Languages: Python, Julia, MATLAB & C++. ML Frameworks: Tensorflow, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, & GPy. Distributed Computing: JASMIN, Fawcett (DAMTP HPC System), UCL High Energy Physics Linux Cluster, AWS Batch. Unix-like OS: Debian-Based Linux Systems & MacOS. Basic HTML & CSS. Git, LATEX.

Education

Pembroke College, University of Cambridge

Cambridge, UK

PhD. Applied Mathematics - Application of Artificial Intelligence

October 2020 – Present

- o Awarded UKRI EPSRC funding to study at the CDT in the Application of Artificial Intelligence for Environmental Risks.
- o Research Topic- 'Deep learning to predict dynamics on an inertial manifold of mid-latitude jet systems'.
 - Co-Supervised by Professors Peter Haynes & Rich Kerswell at DAMTP.
- o Teaching 2022: Supervised Part II Computer Science Deep Neural Networks.
- o Organised Workshops 2022: Cambridge Centre for Climate Science Machine Learning for Climate Science Workshop.
 - Along with 2 other graduate students, we organised a workshop introducing Machine Learning to researchers in the atmospheric sciences with 3 interactive sessions & a hackathon implementing ML on real world atmospheric data.
 - Attendance reached capacity with 30 attendees. Resources can be found here.

University College, University of London

Bloomsbury, London

BSc. Physical Natural Science - Theoretical Physics

September 2017 – June 2020

- o 1st Class overall 1st Class in all 3 years & thesis.
- o Thesis: 'Deep Learning Classifier Robustness for Neutrino Event Detection using Domain Adversarial Neural Networks'.
 - [Python:Tensorflow; C++:ROOT]. Supervised by Dr Chris Backhouse.

Tiffin School

Kingston-Upon-Thames, Surrey

- o A-Levels: 2A* in Mathematics & Further Mathematics; 2A in Economics & Physics (2017).
- o AS-Levels: 6A in above subjects & in History & Physical Education (2016). GCSEs: 6A* & 4A grades (2015).

Projects

2021
2020
2019
2019

Work Experience

FTI Consulting

Aldersgate St, City of London

Data Science & Analytics Summer Intern (ref: kyle.johnson@fticonsulting.com)

July 2019 – August 2019

o 8-week summer internship in which I used dynamic & static web-scraping, graph networks, fuzzy token matching & random forests to identify for anomalous activity indicating fraud & money-laundering. [Python, Neo4j, SQL].

Non-Technical Roles

President (ref: gp@pem.cam.ac.uk)

Pembroke College Graduate Parlour

Pembroke College, Cambridge

June 2021 - Present

o Elected to lead the committee of 12 members & sit on committee meetings with senior college fellows to shape the college experience for graduate students, current. Previosuly Events Officer (Oct 2020 – June 2021).

University of London Halls

Lillian-Penson Hall, Tyburnia & International Hall, Bloomsbury

August 2019 – *August* 2020

Resident Advisor (ref: Dr Derrick Chong)

- o Responsibilities included promoting & monitoring residents' personal, mental & social welfare, other pastoral care both throughout the academic year as well as the COVID pandemic, dealing with disciplinary issues & conflict resolution as well as being in charge of organising the social life of the Hall & managing the Lillian-Penson JCR.
- o Prevuously Events Officer Nutford House JCR, University of London (Sept 2017 June 2018).

Department of Physics & Astronomy

University College London, Bloomsbury

Academic Mentor (ref: a.owusu@ucl.ac.uk)

September 2018 – December 2018

o Provided guidance to 10 first year students by running weekly sessions to aid in their adaptation to university & the degree.